businessnewsbuzz.net 2001-07-14

# 

**Privacy Statement for NetCognizance.com**  
[ Back ]

**Correct/Update**

_Webmaster  
NetCognizance.com   
710 E. Ogden Ave., Suite 630   
Naperville, IL 60563   
webmaster@netcognizance.com _

   Welcome to the NetCog Network, owned and produced by NetCognizance.com, Inc. and its subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively referred to as "NetCog.com" or "NetCog").

NetCog Network Products and Services are offered by NetCog through Web pages at, or linked to, the URLs [www.netcog.com](http://www.netcog.com/), [www.netcognizance.com](http://www.netcognizance.com/), and [www.biocognizance.com](http://www.bionetcognizance.com/). All Products and Service on the NetCog Network are made available subject to this Privacy Policy. By using the Products and Services, you agree, without limitation or qualification, to be bound by this Privacy Policy, or any other privacy or data collection policy applicable to any individual NetCog Network Web site.

The NetCog Network Privacy Policy explains our privacy practices and gives detailed answers to the following questions:

1\. What information of mine does the NetCog Network collect?   
2\. What are "cookies" and how does NetCog use them?   
3\. What organization is collecting my information?   
4\. How does the NetCog Network use my information?   
5\. With whom does the NetCog Network share information?   
6\. How can I access, edit or delete my information?   
7\. What is the opt-out policy of the NetCog Network?   
8\. What security measures protect against loss, misuse or alteration of my information?  
9\. How does the NetCog Network comply with the Children's OnlinePrivacy Protection Act (COPPA)?  
10\. What can I do to better protect myself on the Internet?

**Requests for further information or clarifications should be directed to:  
NetCog Privacy Site Coordinator  
NetCognizance.com, Inc.  
710 E. Ogden Ave., Suite 630  
Naperville, IL 60563**

[**webmaster@netcognizance.com**](mailto:webmaster@netcognizance.com) or   

Please note that the NetCog Network contains links to other sites and occasionally allows other sites to be co-branded with the NetCog name. Those sites may have privacy policies that differ from NetCog Network policy.

The NetCog Network Privacy Policy is updated periodically. When changes occur, you will see the word "updated" next to the Privacy Policy link on the main page of each NetCog Network Web site. If we plan to use personally-identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will prominently post the changes before implementing them. 

**1\. What information of mine does the NetCog Network collect?**

  Our goal is to be your favorite Internet destination by providing information and products most relevant to you. To achieve that goal, NetCog must collect information to determine what makes you different from other unique users. (Information collected online is usually defined as either anonymous or personally-identifiable.)

Anonymous information is data that cannot be tied to a specific individual. For example, each time you visit a NetCog Network site, we collect your IP address, referral data, such as last URL you visited before clicking through to a NetCog Network site, and your browser and platform type. We also collect aggregate search terms from search services for Internal reporting and targeted advertising. NetCog collects this user information for product monitoring and improvement, and for targeted advertising. You need not register with NetCog before we can collect this anonymous information. 

Personally-identifiable information is data telling us specifically who you are, such as your name and postal address, which may be collected in addition to the anonymous data described above. We collect personal information in the following ways:

_NetCog Network Registrations:_

You share personally-identifiable information with NetCog when you register to use a NetCog Network site. When you register, you may provide your name, postal address, e-mail address, birth date, gender, ZIP code, telephone number, occupation, marital status and other information. While not all of this data is required, we can best customize your experience with complete and accurate details. When you register, you receive a NetCog Network ID and can take full advantage of NetCog Network offerings, including personalized services. For example, My NetCog uses your network ID to give you customized news and information. 

_Other Registrations:_

We may also ask for personal information at other times, such as when you enter a sweepstakes, contest or promotion sponsored by the NetCog Network.

You are not required to register for any services on the NetCog Network. But, if you choose not to provide the requested information, NetCog may be unable to offer you the personalized services that depend on this information.

_Correspondence:_ If you contact the NetCog Network, we may keep a record of that correspondence. However, we do not collect e-mail addresses of those who communicate with us via e-mail. We use the information provided only to respond to the e-mail or to contact the sender when necessary. 

**2\. What are "cookies" and how does NetCog use them?**

In addition to the personally identifiable information NetCog actively collects when you register, we also passively collect anonymous information using cookies.

A cookie is a small text file, containing a unique identification number, transferred from a Web site to the hard drive of your computer, allowing the site administrator to identify your computer and track its activities on the site. The number identifies your Web browser -- _but not you_ \-- to our computers whenever you visit a NetCog Network site. A cookie will _not_ determine any of your personally-identifiable information, such as your real name and address.

NetCog uses cookies to determine the particular computer you are using, but _nothing more_. Also, since cookies are only text files, they **do not** run like a program on your computer, search it for information or transmit information to anyone.

To help serve you better, NetCog uses cookies to:

  * **Remember your Web browser** , so we can provide personalized services, such as "My NetCog" membership, or track the sites a Web browser has visited on our Network. 
  * **Save your NetCog passwords and preferences** , so you will not have to re-enter them the next time you visit. 
  * **Enhance NetCog Shopping** , by allowing merchants to track business at their online stores and process orders in individual shopping carts. 
  * **Measure traffic patterns** , to measure the popularity of our services and products and to suggest new offerings. 
  * **Estimate audience size and interests** , by determining whether you have viewed a particular display, including advertising, and to avoid repetition. 
  * **Display advertisements**. Third-party advertising networks for NetCog, such as DoubleClick/Sonar, may use cookies when serving advertisements. (Click [here](http://www.sonar.com/content/privacy.htm) for information on our relationship with DoubleClick/Sonar.)  

(Cookies are used on most major Web sites, and most Web browsers are set up to accept them. You can reset your browser to notify you when you have received a cookie, or you can refuse to accept cookies altogether. While NetCog does not require you to use cookies, certain sites and services will not function properly if you refuse all cookies.)

**3\. What organization is collecting my information?**

When you register for a NetCog Network service, the information is collected and maintained solely by NetCog, unless specifically stated upon collection. For example, some NetCog services -- such as auctions, sweepstakes and promotions -- are offered in conjunction with a third-party company. If data is collected and/or maintained by any company other than NetCog, or shared with any other company, we will tell you. If you do not want to share your information with that company, you can choose not to use that service or participate in that activity. (See the Section entitled "With whom does the NetCog Network share information?" for more details on companies providing products and services through NetCog.)

Be aware that NetCog Network sponsors and other advertisers have links on our sites taking you to other sites that may collect personally identifiable information about you. We hope all third parties involved adhere to our privacy policies. However, the NetCog Network Privacy Policy does not cover third-party data collection practices, and we cannot assume responsibility for the actions of third parties.

**4\. How does the NetCog Network use my information?**

  NetCog requests personally-identifiable information from its users so they can enjoy customized experiences across the NetCog Network, including personalization services and interactive communications. Most of the Products and Services are available to you at no cost. In order to provide content and services free of charge, NetCog displays advertisements. The following are examples of how the NetCog Network may use the information it collects:

NetCog offers users the ability to personalize Network content, such as news, custom home page design, newsletters and e-mail alerts.

NetCog uses the aggregate data collected to inform our sponsors of the number of visitors with certain demographic characteristics and the number of visitors who saw and "clicked" on their advertisement. We also provide third-party sponsors with the demographics of visitors who saw and clicked on their advertisement. No personally- identifiable information is disclosed in this process -- only aggregate information.

  NetCog also uses the aggregate data for statistical analyses of the collective characteristics and behavior of our registered users and visitors, to measure user demographics and interest in specific areas of our Network and to analyze how and where to best use our resources. Without such data, we would not know which areas of the NetCog Network are most popular, and we would not be able to change and update our content and services appropriately.

NetCog may sometimes use your information to contact you about changes or enhancements to our Products and Services.

  If you told NetCog you were interested in receiving offers or information from selected sponsors and advertisers, we will send you e-mail about products and services we believe are of interest to you. For those who elect to receive such materials from NetCog or third parties, and indicate so in their profile, we will release personally identifiable information, including name, e-mail address and other information supplied in the NetCog Network registration process.

  NetCog occasionally enters an individual registered user's data automatically when completing forms displayed to collect individual information for the NetCog Network, its advertisers and sponsors.

  If you enter a sweepstakes or a contest on the NetCog Network, we will use the information you provided to contact you if you win. 

NetCog may be required by law enforcement or judicial authorities to provide information on individual users. In matters threatening personal or public safety, NetCog may voluntarily provide information to appropriate governmental agencies.

  **5\. With whom does the NetCog Network share information that is collected?**

  User information may be shared by companies within the NetCog group or with third-party companies outside the NetCog group. In order to provide content and services that match your interests, the NetCog Network has relationships with many of the best service and content companies. Some of these services require registration before they will function properly. You can recognize most of these sites by looking for the joint branding of NetCog and the third-party company. (For example, if you see a logo in the upper-right corner of the page that says "Brought to you by ______," you are on a co-branded site. Other third-party relationships are "private label" relationships, where a company provides technology, services and/or content under NetCog Network branding. 

Whenever you provide registration information on co-branded or private label sites, that data may be shared with the third-parties providing the service. You should read the individual privacy policies of such third-parties before deciding to continue. You can opt-out of sharing your information with them by choosing not to use their service or content.

Following are third-party companies with whom NetCog has contracted to provide you Products and Services. This list may expand or change from time to time.

  * NetCog Affiliate Services. 
  * NetCog contracts with Be Free, Inc. to provide Traffic Affiliate Program services for the NetCog Network. For more information about Be Free's privacy policy, click [here](http://www.befree.com/docs/includes/privacy.htm). 
  * NetCog Shop. 

When you purchase goods or services through NetCog Shop, your credit card and identifying information will be provided to third parties to verify the credit card data. Data you submit when using the NetCog Shop will be provided to individual merchants from whom you order goods or services. Please review carefully the privacy policies of merchants you access through NetCog Shop.

Because your privacy and security are important to us, the personal data you submit when using the NetCog Shop Shopping Cart (including your credit card number, billing, and shipping information) is passed through "secure servers," using technology provided by [Verisign](http://www.verisign.com/), which is a member of the [TRUSTe](http://www.truste.com/) program. For most purchases made through the NetCog Shopping Cart, your credit card is charged electronically and your account number is never presented to the merchant from whom you have purchased.

NetCog contracts with partners to collect feedback from randomly-selected users about their satisfaction with the NetCog site. For more information about the their privacy policies, see our partners page.

In addition to co-branded and private label sites, our site has direct links to other third party sites. Some of them are authorized to use the NetCog Network brands and/or logos. **No third-party sites are covered by this Privacy Policy.** If you believe a site using a NetCog Network brand and/or logo does not follow an acceptable privacy policy, please contact the NetCog Privacy Site Coordinator by e-mail at [privacy@netcog.com](mailto:privacy@netcog.com).

**6\. How can I access, edit or delete my information?**

The NetCog Network allows registered users to access and edit the personal information in their user profiles. For most NetCog Network membership sites, you can access your user profile by following these steps:

\- Go directly to [**http://www.netcognizance.com.**](http://www.netcognizance.com/) You will receive a prompt to log in with your NetCog Network Member Name and password. You will then be taken to the Membership Information page, which contains your user profile. To update a field, click the appropriate Edit button. Make your changes and click the Update button to save them.   
For some other sites on the NetCog Network, you will have to follow different steps to update the personal information in your user profile.

\- NetCog Unsubscribe at [**http://www.netcog.com/unsubscribemem.asp**](http://www.netcog.com/unsubscribemem.asp): After you log in, click on "Check My Account" then "Update Your User Profile." You must use your NetCog Network ID, password and e-mail address.

  **7\. What is the opt-out policy of the NetCog Network?**

  The NetCog Network allows you to opt-out of receiving information on NetCog updates and new services, as well as direct mail offers from selected NetCog Network service providers and sponsors. This can be done when information is initially collected or during the editing or updating process. The instructions to opt out of most NetCog Network e-mail newsletters and direct mail communications are the same as those for editing user information profiles. Simply follow these steps:

\- Go directly to [http://www.netcognizance.com](http://www.netcognizance.com/). You will receive a prompt to log in to the Network with your NetCog Network Member Name and password. After you log in, you will be taken to the Membership Information page containing your e-mail subscriptions. Click the Edit button under the Email Subscriptions banner. Make the desired changes and click the Update button to save them. All NetCog Network newsletters and direct e-mail communications have simple unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each e-mail.

**8\. What security measures protect against loss, misuse or alteration of my information?**

The NetCog Network has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of your user data. Only authorized employees can access your information in our databases and host servers. While we cannot guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration to data will not occur, we take strict precautions to prevent such occurrences. Particularly sensitive information, such as your credit card number collected for a transaction, is encrypted prior to transmission. 

You are ultimately responsible for the security of your NetCog Network ID and password. Take care when using and storing them. NetCog recommends that you do not divulge your password to anyone. Log off of your browser at the end of each computer session to deny others access your personal information and correspondence, especially if you share a computer or use one in a public place, such as a library or Internet cafe.

**9\. How does the NetCog Network comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA)?**

Parents of children under 13 can get detailed information on the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) of 1998 and the NetCog Network's compliance with COPPA by clicking [here](http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/pubs/buspubs/coppa.htm).

We DO NOT collect online contact information without prior parental notification or consent, and we include an opportunity for parents to prevent use of the information and participation in the activity. Without prior parental consent, online information will only be used to respond directly to a child's request and will not be used for other purposes without prior parental consent.

  We DO NOT collect personally-identifiable offline contact information without prior parental consent.

We DO NOT distribute to third parties any personally-identifiable information without prior parental consent.

We DO NOT entice visitors with the prospect of a special game, prize or other activity to divulge more information than is needed to participate in an activity.

**10\. What can I do to better protect myself on the Internet?**

_Know the risks._

Meeting new people in an online community (chat room, forum, newsgroup, message board, Web page, etc.) is a feature of the Internet. But always be careful about disclosing personal information that can be collected and used by persons outside the NetCog Network to send unsolicited e-mail messages. To curtail unsolicited e-mail, NetCog blocks certain e-mail addresses and domains from sending messages to e-mail addresses on our domains. We make chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to our users. However, any information disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution.

_Educate yourself._

Search the Web for information about how to protect your privacy. Look for a privacy policy on the Web sites you visit. A good place to start is [**TRUSTe**](http://www.truste.org/), an independent, non-profit organization with a mission to build trust and confidence in the Internet. The Federal Trade Commission has a Web site with useful information on being a [Savvy Internet Traveler](http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/pubs/online/sitesee/index.html), along with other [privacy initiatives](http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/index.html). Additional privacy resources are available by clicking on any of the following links: 

Department of Education: Parents Guide to the Internet  
<http://www.ed.gov/pubs/parents/internet/>

Better Business Bureau (BBB)  

The Privacy Rights Clearinghouse  
<http://www.privacyrights.org/>

Center for Democracy and Technology  
<http://www.cdt.org/privacy/> \- Data Privacy  
<http://www.cdt.org/privacy/guide/> \- Guide to Online Privacy

Direct Marketing Association (DMA)  
<http://www.the-dma.org/>

Electronic Frontier Foundation - non-profit dedicated to protecting public interest in online privacy. [http://www.eff.org](http://www.eff.org/)

EPIC.org (Electronic Privacy Information Center)  

Georgetown Internet Privacy Study  
<http://www.msb.edu/faculty/culnanm/gippshome.html>

NetCoalition.com  

Network Advertising Initiative  
<http://www.networkadvertising.org/>

Online Privacy Alliance  
<http://www.privacyalliance.org/>

_Tell your children: "Never talk to strangers!"_

While NetCog works hard to protect children on our network sites, we cannot protect their privacy once they leave. Teach children not to reveal their names or personal information to anyone they encounter on the Internet. Instruct them not to fill out any forms or register at any Web site without your knowledge and consent. Take advantage of the Internet's online resources for parents.

Use PGP (Pretty Good Privacy) [http://www.pgp.com](http://www.pgp.com/) or another encryption program.   
Last updated January 1, 2001.

_**TRUSTe** Certification_

NetCog is a licensee of the **TRUSTe** Privacy Program. **TRUSTe** is an independent, non-profit organization with a mission to build trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the principles of disclosure and informed consent. Because NetCog wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, we have agreed to disclose our information practices and have our privacy practices reviewed and audited for compliance by **TRUSTe**. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, contact [**TRUSTe**](http://www.truste.org/users/users_watchdog.html), who will serve as a liaison with the NetCog Network to resolve your concerns. You may also contact them with general questions about the **TRUSTe** Seal Program: 

**TRUSTe** Certification  
1180 Coleman Avenue, Suite 202  
San Jose, CA 95110  
(408) 342-1940  
(408) 342-1950 (Fax)  

To Change/Modify Information:

NetCog.com gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided:

  * Send e-mail to [privacy@netcog.com](mailto:privacy@netcog.com)
  * Reply to an e-mail list according to the instructions at the bottom of the message. 
  * Click on the link at the bottom of a message received from an e-mail list 

_Notice_

NetCog.com reserves the right to change its privacy policy at any time. Notifications of changes in our privacy practices will be issued in one or more of the following ways:

  * Posting of a message on the [**www.netcog.com**](http://www.netcog.com/) Web site 
  * Users voluntarily viewing the privacy statement for periodic changes 
  * Contacting NetCog.com 

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, our privacy practices or your dealings with the NetCog Network, contact:

Webmaster  
NetCognizance.com  
710 E. Ogden Ave., Suite 630  
Naperville, IL 60563  
866-4NETCOG
